YU CAO

Computational Linguist

@ yc825@linguistics.rutgers.edu

pterosdiacos.github.io

in www.linkedin.com/in/yu-cao-pdiacos

EXPERIENCES

Ontology Linguist

Facebook via PRO Unlimited

1 08/2019 - 10/2019

Redmond, WA

- Worked at Assistant Cross-Functional Group
- Prototyped models for cross-domain semantic parsing for question answering, using PyTorch
- Automated inferences and sub-ontology extraction in OWL 2 ontology knowledge graphs, using Python

Teaching Assistant

Rutgers University

1 09/2018 - 08/2020

New Brunswick, NJ

• Courses taught: Intro to Linguistic Theory, Invented Languages

Research Assistant

The Chinese University of Hong Kong

12/2014 - 07/2015

♥ Hong Kong, China

- Worked at Center for Sign Linguistics and Deaf Studies
- Provided linguistic expertise and assisted in developing a Chinese grammatical knowledge assessment software for deaf/hard of hearing children

EDUCATION

Rutgers University

Ph.D. in Linguistics

09/2016 - Present

New Brunswick, NJ

The Chinese University of Hong Kong

M.A. in Chinese Linguistics & Language Acquisition

1 09/2013 - 06/2014

♥ Hong Kong, China

Sichuan Normal University

B.A. in Teaching Chinese as a Second Language

1 09/2009 - 06/2013

Chengdu, China

PUBLICATIONS

 Automated fact-value distinction in court opinions European Journal of Law and Economics 2020.

♣ Yu Cao, Daniel Chen & Elliot Ash.

Automated classification of fact vs. value statements in written judicial decisions

Investigating BERT's knowledge of language: Five analysis methods with NPIs

Proceedings of EMNLP 2019.

▲ Alex W., Yu Cao & 14 others (equal contribution).

Team role: constructed and conducted the main transfer learning experiments

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Linguistics specialized in computational

linguistics, semantics, syntax, discourse analysis. Strong critical-thinking and problem-

solving skills.

Computation 10+ years of experiences in

algorithms and data structure. The First Prize in National Olympiad in Informatics in Provinces 2007, China

PROJECTS

Graph representation of meaning

(dissertation research () repo)

- Designed a graph based semantic representation that encodes natural language quantification and plurality.
- Developed a CCG-based semantic parser constructing graphs from texts using *Python*.

Incremental topological sorting (LingBuzz post)

- Designed algorithms for topological sorting under uncertain conditions.
- Improved on resorting time complexity with dynamic updating strategies.

SKILLS

Technical

- Machine learning algorithms, NLP/NLU
- Python, C, Scikit-learn, PyTorch, Tensorflow
- Linguistic analysis, symbolic logic, statistics

ML/NLP Coursework

Natural language processing

1 09/2020

Introduction to deep learning

m 07/2020

m HSE@Coursera

Machine learning

07/2020

0 <u>m</u> Stanford@Coursera

• Seminar: Linguistic knowledge in reusable sentence encoders

1 05/2019

m NYU

Graph formalisms for meaning representations
 m 07/2018
 m NASSLLI@CMU

Languages

ENG (fluent) CHN (native) JPN (JLPT N1)